so this is the hero phrase i really need
you to punch that word hit it nice and
hard give it a nice big billboard
so we're going to punch you in and then
we're going to roll and i want you to do
an abc on that all right so
we're rolling let's go what
news from the booth hi villagers welcome
back to the voice over village i'm rick
mciver your village idiot today
we are going to cover voiceover terms if
you were a little confused by the intro
to this video
don't worry we're going to explain a few
of those things i was inspired to do
this video
by a fellow voice actor by the name of
mike delgadio he did a great video on
voiceover terms and i'll put a link to
it right up there
but he missed a few some that i see on a
regular basis so i thought i'd fill in
the blanks
now this is going to be a three-part
series the first one is going to focus
on performance based terms
the second one is going to focus on
microphone-based terms
and the third one is going to focus
mostly on production and
technology terms and things that have to
do with software and recording
let's get to it the first one is sides
sides
means the script or the copy things like
that
that's what sides refers to the next is
tempo i'll have a director tell me
i need to change the tempo of this i
need to pick up the tempo it's kind of
just the rhythm of the piece go faster
go slower
sometimes you'll hear it referred to as
pacing the next is line
read when someone gives you a line read
when a director is there and he's
reading the line to you what they want
is for you to read that line exactly
like
they read it so that's why it's called a
line reading
you can also ask a director for a line
reading
and say that i need a line reading to
understand what you're talking about
and then do your own version of it so
it's not exact just
parrot of what the director says but
sometimes
that's what the director wants just a
straight line read our next one is pick
up
now a pickup is something that you do
after you're kind of
finished with the job the client might
come back to you and say i need a pick
up for this phrase
and it could be that you flubbed it or
it could be that you mispronounced it
or they might have changed it in the
script but it's called a pickup and so
what
needs to happen is you listen to what
you did and then there's this little
section that you actually
redo so that's called a pickup booth
junkie referred to something called a
take now a take is each
try that you do for a particular part
right so
if i go to record a sentence it would be
take one and if i did it a second time
it'd be take
two one thing that i wanted to make
clear was that
you're not responsible as an actor right
as the talent like he says
you don't have to keep track of that the
engineer will keep track of the takes
for you
there's no way to kind of keep in your
mind oh this is
take six and uh i should emulate take
two or don't worry about that they will
keep track of that for you
you don't have to worry about it the
next one is something called efforts
efforts are those sounds that you make
when you're like if you're doing a
cartoon and you have a fight scene
it's those or you fall off a horse
or someone says do the wilhelm scream
right
that's an effort um sometimes they're
called ad-libs or
non-word sounds but i hear them mostly
referred to as
efforts and they're usually done at the
end of your session for the day
basically because a lot of them are
screams and yells and
things that actually kind of roast your
throat so they want that
towards the end of the recording session
rather than the beginning
all right let's talk about
conversational versus announcer you'll
hear this
a lot i need a conversational read um
or a non-announcer read what that really
means is that they want
the talent to read the script very
casually like they were just talking to
their friend in the elevator or on a
park bench or whatever
it's just a casual kind of read
and technically that kind of looks like
you know you don't pay attention to the
punctuation
perfectly or it could be that you kind
of don't hit
all your consonants formally it's really
relaxed
and a lot of it's kind of throwaway it's
just
just a very calm relaxed tone
as opposed to the announcer read now the
announcer read
is very formal all of the consonants are
are observed religiously there are
spaces in between words
the punctuation is very important and
it's very
projected that kind of read was popular
back in the 30s and 40s because you know
those
radios you had to cut through and so
people with big voices
were very clear with their diction and
that and was called the announcer read
but you don't hear that much anymore
because we don't need that kind of style
anymore and
it's kind of associated with that used
car salesman
kind of pitch and clients typically like
a more
realistic relaxed style of read and so
that's
conversational all right these are just
about a little bit of mic technique
you might hear a director or an engineer
say
i need you to get more on axis well what
axis means is if you look at this mic
this is a top address mic the sound goes
in here if i go off to the side like
this
it gets really quiet when i go off to
the side
that's called going off axis when i'm
talking into the microphone i'm on
axis now i can talk across the
microphone so i don't
pop up my p's with plosives as long as
the microphone is
pointed at my mouth then i'm on axis
this is the axis it's like the line that
comes out
of the microphone you might hear a
director say i need you more
on axis and that means line up with
where you talk into the microphone
you might also hear directors say you
sound very sibilant um
mike covered plosives which is that
sound in his video
but he didn't talk about sibilance
probably because he has a very deep
resonant
smooth voice and doesn't ever have to
worry about that
if you have a higher head voice and you
have a lot of nasal tones in your voice
you might come across this term
sibilance
and it's that s sound and it can be very
cutting
sometimes if you are you know because
think about when people listen
to you in their headphones and that s
sound comes through it's like ah it's
like a little needle in your eardrum
that's called sibilance and there are
some techniques you can use to get over
that i will put a link to this video up
here
that covers how to get rid of your
sibilance
you might have a director say to you
give me more smile
more sparkle more energy it just means
hey you have to up your attitude bigger
than you think you do especially for
voice actors like me
who have this kind of resonant deep
voice i have to
over smile sometimes when i am doing my
work because
otherwise i sound like i'm mad i'm not
mad
so i have to give it more smile you
physically
have to put a smile on your face when
you're talking a really big one
because it makes a difference in the
recording you might have a director say
hey
i need you to bury this phrase that kind
of means
move through it or throw it away it's
it's a phrase that
is there it needs to be there but it's
not really important because if you try
to make everything
important in a script then the important
things don't sound
important so you might get a director
that says to you hey bury this part and
move on to
this other part and billboard it that
means
punch it up you know this is the hero
word or the hero phrase
it's the important thing and that also
could be called billboarding or
punch it which is the opposite of bury
it
you might also have a director say hey
there's too much dead air in here i need
you to tighten up i need you to bring in
your cues
well that means the spaces between the
words or the sentences
need to flow it just needs to come out
quicker because if it's
you know if you're leaving too much
space in between words
that is dead air and they don't want
that you got to keep that pace up and
keep that thing moving
another thing the director might say to
you is i need you to bring it up
i need you to bring your tone up um and
what they're talking about is
taking your voice out of your chest
which is kind of where my voice
naturally sits it's down here and in my
throat and in my chest and you can if
you put your hand
on your chest you can feel it you know
you vibrate
and when they say bring it up that means
take your voice and put more air in it
bring it up into your nasal cavity this
area up here is called your
mask that's what they call it an acting
world if the director says
bring it up that's what they mean it
means put your voice
up here in your head in your mask and
sinuses
so that has more air and it sounds maybe
a little bit younger
than if you're down here where my voice
naturally sits
something you might hear uh but is not
necessarily a direction
is something called punch and roll or
we're gonna punch in
and what that means is that um you know
up to a certain point in the script
you got to a place and then they need
you to start from
maybe not at the beginning of the
paragraph but maybe two or three
sentences in
so they'll punch you in at that point
and that is kind of like you get a lead
in which is what you say
and then it when you're supposed to
start talking the recording starts and
that's called
punching you in and then the roll part
means it's just gonna keep
going right you keep going and going and
going until the director tells you to
stop so that's
punch and roll it's an old term
because of you know radio days and tapes
that
rolled on the tape recorder this doesn't
really apply anymore
in the digital age however the term has
stuck
and also that's what rolling means if an
engineer says we're rolling it what it
really means is
we're recording but because of the olden
days when the tape would roll
on the spool it called it rolling and it
just stuck
and the last term that i want to bring
up is something called the glass
you may hear uh actors and directors say
hey i've been on that side of the glass
or this side of the glass or
if you're uh at a studio and uh they
want you to go step into the recording
booth to record they'll say hey go get
on that other side of the glass
it's time to get on the that side of the
glass what they're referring to is
there's
usually a really large piece of glass
so the engineer and director can see you
as a voice actor
and you can in turn see them and so
you're on one side of the glass
recording and they're on the other side
of the glass recording and so
it's called the glass now you know
so there you go performance based terms
things you have to know
as a voice actor i hope these terms are
helpful if they
are let me know leave a like that would
be awesome thank you very much
and if you're confused by a term leave
me a comment
let me know that didn't make any sense
or if you hear something that i didn't
cover
leave me a comment and i'll answer you
and let you know what i think that term
means
anyway thanks for watching i really
appreciate it until next time